

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary

An Information Systems Engineering student at University Tunku Abdul Rahman, with around 3+ years of experience with specialties in frontend/backend web development, and infrastructure operations.

Loves to participate in the open source community through discussions, and open source contributions. Prefers to use Unix-like (Linux/MacOS) systems for software development, loves to tinker with the system, and eager to learn new things.

Skills_

Languages Typescript, Javascript, Python, Perl5, C++

Tooling Git, Bash, Linux, Mobx

Frameworks React, Hapi, Django, Django Rest Framework, Flask, Scrapy, Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, Kalidokit

Industry Knowledge CI/CD, Agile Software Development, Data Structures and Algorithms

Work Experience

555 Comic Co. Remote

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANT

Oct. 2022 - Dec. 2022

- Drastically improved the maintainability, and reduced possibility of bugs in an application by refactoring existing non-React code to React.
- · Participated in the development of a motion tracking application that converts motion data into anime style comic through AI.

Vox Sea Sdn. Bhd. Remote

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANT

May. 2022 - Jun. 2022

• Created a Python utility library for formatting markdown text to its equivalent on several social media channels.

Vox Sea Sdn. Bhd. Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Feb. 2021 Mar. 2021
- $\bullet \ \, \text{Built, and deployed backend applications using Django, Kubernetes, Docker, and PostgreSQL}.$
- Responsible for development of parts of a REST API that interacts with an AI back-end.
- Responsible for deployment of the back-end REST API using Kubernetes and Docker.
- Guided junior developers through technical problems.
- Participated in daily scrum/agile meetings (technical) and weekly company meetings.

Binary Group Services Sdn. Bhd.

Cyberjaya, Selangor, Malaysia

Dec. 2018 - Dec. 2020

• Implemented a chat application by integrating SendBird's chat API.

- Developed server side services for automated payments using NodeJS, Docker, and PostgreSQL.
- Coordinate with UI/UX to implement designs for our web applications using tools such as Abstract, Zeplin and Invision.
- Collaborated with compliance to make sure our software complies with the laws.
- Help our recruitment team with proctoring new tech candidates in our hackathon.
- Autonomously create, manage, and executing tasks at hand.
- Learned and adopted new technology quickly (Javascript/Perl5).
- · Participated in typical software development process such as sprint meetings, and code reviews.
- Use React, Grunt, Mobx, Webpack and SASS to build and maintain frontend applications.

Education

University Tunku Abdul Rahman

Kampar, Perak, Malaysia

BACHELOR OF INFORMATION SYSTEMS (HONOURS) INFORMATION SYSTEMS ENGINEERING

May. 2021 - May. 2024

3.0 CGP/

- Obtained an A in "Data Structure and Algorithmic Problem Solving" which is a course introducing students to data structure and algorithms.
- Developing an IOT debug tool to assist in research work.

JULY 17, 2023 YII KUO CHONG · RÉSUMÉ 1